Register of the Survey of Race Relations records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Minor Documents, 1907-1934 (Boxes 33-38)
  - "Interview with Louise Leung," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 34: 63)
    1 page; Americanization: Second generation, Education, and Vocational problems; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Julia Suski," language problem, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 34: 64)
    1 page; Americanization: Second generation and Family problems, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Y. Shimanuchi, editor, Los Angeles Japanese American," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 14 (Box-folder 34: 65)
    1 page; Family life, Americanization: Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mrs. Kunisaki, Puente," by William C. Smith, 1924 September 12 (Box-folder 34: 66)
    1 page; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Life History of a Japanese," by Suzanne McKelvey (Box-folder 34: 67)
    4 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - Portion of a letter from Professor James H. Hyde to President Harding regarding the Japanese question of California (Box-folder 34: 68)
    6 pages; Investigations: Legislation; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - "The Essentials of Mexican Culture," extracts of an interview by Dr. Hewitt? (Box-folder 34: 69)
    3 pages; Aesthetic, Morals; Mexican; Northern California) - Missing
  - Interview, Dr. Hewitt, archaeologist (Box-folder 34: 70)
    1 page; Competition and land: Agriculture and Labor, Disease; Mexican; Northern California) - Missing
  - Interview by Dr. Hewitt - Doheny Survey (Box-folder 34: 71)
    1 page; Communities; Competition and Land: Labor; Race consciousness; Mexican; Northern California) - Missing
  - "The Japanese Question in Connection with the Johnson Immigration Bill," speech, Jesse H. McLafferty (Box-folder 34: 72)
    3 pages; Investigations: Legislation; Population: Immigration; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - Oriental comment, Far Eastern Fortnightly, 1919 September 1 (Box-folder 34: 73)
    1 page; Race consciousness; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - American Citizenship Council (Box-folder 34: 74)
    1 page; Americanization; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Hybridization of Races," paper, by Edna McKinley, State Teachers College, San Francisco (Box-folder 34: 75)
    4 pages; Population, Intermarriage; Northern California
  - "Just How Wide Should We Open Our Door to Japan?," paper, Ethel Coller, State Teachers College, San Francisco (Box-folder 34: 76)
    3 pages; Race consciousness, Intermarriage, Population; Japanese; Northern California
  - "Mrs. K.," sketch, by Lola E. Brown (Box-folder 34: 77)
    1 page; Americanization; Japanese; Northern California
  - Reminiscences of an Americanization teacher (Box-folder 34: 78)
  - Reminiscences of an Americanization teacher (Box-folder 34: 79)
  - Sketch, Fred F., Americanization teacher (Box-folder 34: 80)
    2 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Northern California
  - Japanese at Selma, California (Box-folder 34: 81)
    1 page; Americanization, Racial traits; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Letter from an Americanization teacher to Vaughn MacCaughey, 1924 March 18 (Box-folder 34: 82)
    2 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Northern California
  - Letter from Edwin E. Grant to Immigration Commissioner (Box-folder 34: 83)
    1 page; Social disorganization: Vice and crime; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Letter from William C. Pond to Vaughn MacCaughey, 1924 April 3 (Box-folder 34: 84)
    3 pages; Life histories, Goodwill; Chinese; Northern California
  - Interview with prominent orchard man, Livingston, California (Box-folder 34: 85)
    1 page; Americanization, Communities; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - Personal sketch of Paul Scharrenburg, San Francisco (Box-folder 34: 86)
    1 page; Race consciousness: Conflict; Northern California
  - Personal sketch of Torao Kawasaki, Japanese consulate, San Francisco (Box-folder 34: 87)
    1 page; Life histories, Intermarriage; Japanese; Northern California
  - Personal sketch of Theodore Fieldbrave, Berkeley (Box-folder 34: 88)
    1 page; Life histories, Goodwill: Religious activities; Hindu; Northern California
  - Extract from letter to Vaughn MacCaughey from Mrs. Whitcher, Americanization teacher, Castroville, California (Box-folder 34: 89)
    12 pages; Americanization; Goodwill: Religious activities; Racial traits; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - "California's Threatened Hegira of Japanese," by V. S. McClatchy (Box-folder 34: 90)
    4 pages; Investigations: Historical; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Livingston," by Mary Naka (Box-folder 34: 91)
    12 pages; Communities, Americanization: Education, Population, Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Northern California
  - Letter from Japanese citizen, Livingston (Box-folder 34: 92)
    3 pages; Americanization, Communities; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Letter to Vaughan MacCaughey from Suzanne McKelvey regarding Japanese question, 1924 March 12 (Box-folder 34: 93)
    3 pages; Race consciousness; Japanese; Northern California
  - "Mrs. I. ---," sketch, by Marda McKenrick (Box-folder 34: 94)
    1 page; Americanization; Japanese; Northern California) -Missing
  - "Mallie Minn, Korean Girl," by Mrs. Park (Box-folder 34: 95)
    2 pages; Life histories; Korean; Northern California) - Missing
  - Japanese family problem, essay (Box-folder 34: 96)
    6 pages; Americanziation, Communities; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Mrs. L.," sketch, by Marda McKendrick (Box-folder 34: 97)
    3 pages; Communities, Life histories; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Mary," sketch, by Marda McKendrick (Box-folder 34: 98)
    3 pages; Life histories, Goodwill; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Experience with Orientals," by Solomon Blur, University of California (Box-folder 34: 99)
    1 page; Americanization, Race consciousness; Northern California) - Missing
  - Commonwealth Club of California, minutes of meeting, section on agriculture (Box-folder 34: 100)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture and Labor; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Letter from Bakersfield, California, teacher on contacts with Orientals, to Vaughan MacCaughey, 1924 March 31 (Box-folder 34: 101)
    2 pages; Racial traits, Americanization; Chinese and Japanese; Northern California
  - Report, Hindus in the United States (Box-folder 34: 102)
    4 pages; Investigations: Statistics, Goodwill: Religious activities; Hindu; Northern California) – Missing
  - The Hindus in America (Box-folder 34: 103)
    6 pages; Investigations, Race consciousness, Goodwill; Hindu; Northern California) - Missing
  - Chinese and Japanese newspapers in San Francisco (Box-folder 34: 104)
    1 page; Communities; Northern California) – Missing
  - Minutes, American Loyalty League (Box-folder 34: 105)
    9 pages; Americanization; Northern California) - Missing
  - "The History and Problem of Angel Island," by Mary Naka, Japanese graduate, Mills College, 1922 (Box-folder 34: 106)
    5 pages; Population: Immigration; Chinese; Northern California
  - Appeal to U.S. Supreme Court testing Anti-Alien Land Laws (Box-folder 34: 107)
    3 pages; Competition and land: Cropping contract, Investigations: Legislation,; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Appeal to U.S. Supreme Court testing Anti-Alien Land Laws (Box-folder 34: 108)
    2 pages; Competition and land, Investigations: Legislation, Ownership of stock; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Appeal to U.S. Supreme Court testing Anti-Alien Land Laws (Box-folder 34: 109)
    2 pages; Competition and land, Investigations: Legislation, Leasing; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - Appeal from U.S. District Court, Western District of Washington, to U.S. Supreme Court (Box-folder 34: 110)
    7 pages; Competition and land, Investigations: Legislation, Leasing) - Missing
  - "No Shortage of Orchard Labor," by V. S. McClatchy (Box-folder 34: 111)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture and Labor; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Miller Freeman and the Survey," Great Northern Daily News, translation (Box-folder 34: 112)
    2 pages; Race consciousness: Public opinion, Strike; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Points for discussion at the Japanese Conference Committee meeting (Box-folder 34: 113)
    4 pages; Race consciousness, Investigations: Legislation; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Japanese population on the Pacific Coast and Mountain States, compiled by the Japanese Conference Committee, San Francisco (Box-folder 34: 114)
    2 pages; Population; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Opinion concerning the legality of employment contract – Algernon Crofton (Box-folder 34: 115)
    1 page; Competition and land: Employment contract, Investigations: Legislation; Northern California) - Missing
  - Copy of contract of employment (Box-folder 34: 116)
    1 page; Competition and land: Employment contract, Investigations: Legislation,; Northern California) - Missing
  - Paper written by Japanese student in reply to questionnaire on race relations (Box-folder 34: 117)
    4 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Interview with S. Kato, pastor, Japanese Christian Church, Berkeley (Box-folder 34: 118)
    3 pages; Communities, Race consciousness; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - "Diary of A Forty-Niner," extract, by Chauncey L. Canfield (Box-folder 34: 119)
    1 page; Race consciousness, Competition and land; Chinese; Northern California
  - Report, Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, regarding Japanese question: Conclusions 3, 8, 12 (Box-folder 34: 120)
    1 page; Competition and land: Agriculture and Labor; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - Report, Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, regarding Japanese question: Conclusions 10, 11 (Box-folder 34: 121)
    1 page; Americanization, Investigations: Legislation; Japanese; Northern California) – Missing
  - Report, National Industrial Conference Board: Immigration Bill severely criticized (Box-folder 34: 122)
    3 pages; Investigations: Legislation; Northern California) – Missing
  - Contacts of Professor Ches. F. Shaw (Box-folder 34: 123)
    - Chinese and Japanese
      1 page; Racial traits; Chinese and Japanese; Northern California
    - Hindus
      1 page; Racial traits; Hindu; Northern California
    - Armenians
      3 pages; Racial traits; American; Northern California
  - Experience of Fresno citizen regarding Japanese (Box-folder 34: 124)
    - 18-year-old Japanese school boy
    - Japanese in Fresno High School
  - Questionnaire on Japanese problem submitted by George Shima, President of Japanese Association of America (Box-folder 34: 125)
    132 pages; Americanization, Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Remarks, Oriental children, Miss Rippe, Americanization teacher, Fresno Public Schools (Box-folder 34: 126)
    2 pages; Americanization, Social disorganization; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Flora Belle Jan," Chinese flapper, Fresno (Box-folder 34: 127)
    3 pages; Americanization; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Remarks, crime conditions, Chester Warlow, Fresno Crime Commission (Box-folder 34: 128)
    1 page; Social disorganization, Social disorganization: Vice and crime, Tongs; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Remarks, O. M. Akers, Probation Officer, Fresno County (Box-folder 34: 129)
    1 page; Social disorganization: Delinquency and disease; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - Remarks, Chinatown police squad, Fresno (Box-folder 34: 130)
    2 pages; Social disorganization, Tongs, Americanization; Chinese; Northern California) - Missing
  - "Two Schools for Chinese," by Mrs. Park, 1924 August (Box-folder 34: 131)
    4 pages; Goodwill, Slave girls; Chinese; Northern California
  - Interview with Miho Catherine Ota (Box-folder 34: 132)
    4 pages; Life histories, Goodwill, Americanization: Accommodation; Japanese; Seattle) – Missing
  - Interview with Mrs. Komie Iga (Box-folder 34: 133)
    2 pages; Life histories, Competition and land: Labor; Race consciousness; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Yaeimachi Sugimachi (Box-folder 34: 134)
    1 page; Life histories; Japanese; Seattle) – Missing
  - Letter from young woman regarding Japanese question (Box-folder 34: 135)
    1 page; Race consciousness: Public opinion; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Extract from letter of a teacher in Washington regarding the Chinese (Box-folder 34: 136)
    1 page; Americanization; Chinese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Statement by Bradstreet (Box-folder 34: 137)
    1 page; Competition and land; Business; Chinese and Japanese; Seattle) – Missing
  - Japanese Province Club and Business Club (Box-folder 34: 138)
    1 page; Communities; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Seattle Japanese Nurses Association (Box-folder 34: 139)
    1 page; Communities, Competition and land: Labor; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - The Japanese Laundry Union (Box-folder 34: 140)
    1 page; Competition and land: Labor, Race consciousness; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Japanese labor unions (Box-folder 34: 141)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Labor; Japanese; Seattle) – Missing
  - Index to the Far Eastern Fortnightly bulletins, Far Eastern Bureau (Box-folder 34: 142)
    12 pages; Investigations: Historical; Japanese and Chinese; Seattle) - Missing
  - North American Times, Japanese publication in Seattle, extract (Box-folder 34: 143)
    1 page; Population: Immigration; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Report, Japanese A. B. General Contractors (Box-folder 34: 144)
    1 page; Competition and land: Labor, Investigations: Statistics; Japanese and Filipino; Seattle) - Missing
  - Japanese working for railroads, Chicago, Milwaukee, and St. Paul (Box-folder 34: 145)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Labor, Investigations: Statistics; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - "What the General Public Knows and Does Not Know About the Japanese Question," term paper by Don Greiner, Ballard High School, Seattle, Washington, 1924 May 8 (Box-folder 34: 146)
    8 pages; Race consciousness: Public opinion; Japanese; Seattle
  - Salvation Army Fresh Air Camp for Japanese boys (Box-folder 34: 147)
    2 pages; Goodwill, Communities, Americanization; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Reply to teacher's questionnaire (Box-folder 34: 148)
    1 page; Americanization: Education; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Supreme Court, Japanese charged with murder in the first degree (Box-folder 34: 149)
    16 pages; Social disorganization: Vice and crime; Japanese; Seattle
  - Japan Society Bulletin (Box-folder 34: 150)
    3 pages; Goodwill; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Nobuo Hirai (Box-folder 34: 151)
    2 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Questionnaire by S. Minami (Box-folder 34: 152)
    3 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Seattle
  - Interview with Taguchi, farmer, Green Lake District (Box-folder 34: 153)
    3 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture, Americanization; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Tanejiro Gima (Box-folder 34: 154)
  - Interview with Mrs. Tada Sasaki (Box-folder 34: 155)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture, Race consciousness; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with T. Matsumura (Box-folder 34: 156)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Business and labor; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Mr. and Mrs. Nakata (Box-folder 34: 157)
    4 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness, Racial traits; Japanese; Seattle) – Missing
  - Interview with Abe Gapanese, Congregational Minister (Box-folder 34: 158)
    2 pages; Communities; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Tatsumi Sato (Box-folder 34: 159)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Seichi Konzo (Box-folder 34: 160)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Other: Industry; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - The Japanese May Flower – The Peony (Box-folder 34: 161)
    1 page; Heritages; Japanese; Seattle) – Missing
  - The American Legion point of view in Washington (Box-folder 34: 162)
    1 page; Race consciousness, Investigations: Legislation; Japanese; Seattle
  - A Filipino's reply to a sociology questionnaire (Box-folder 34: 163)
    5 pages; Life histories; Filipino; Seattle - Missing
  - Viewpoint of Thomas N. Swale, lawyer, Seattle, Chairman of the Oriental Committee, National American Legion (Box-folder 34: 164)
  - Yoshio Ando, Franklin High School, 1924 June 5 (Box-folder 34: 165)
  - Brief interview with two Japanese students who just arrived in the U.S. (Box-folder 34: 166)
    1 page; Life histories, Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Reply to life history questionnaire (Box-folder 34: 167)
  - Life history of student, Bellingham State Normal School (Box-folder 34: 168)
    2 pages; Life histories; Filipino; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with C. S. Whitcomb regarding Japanese labor (Box-folder 34: 169)
    1 page; Competition and land: Labor and business; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Interview with J. M. Homer regarding dealings with the Japanese (Box-folder 34: 170)
    1 page; Goodwill, Competition and land: Business; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Copy of circular letter in Japanese from Japanese Association urging attendance of school children at school, El Monte, California (Box-folder 34: 171)
    1 page; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Letter from Principal P. J. Cooney, El Monte High, to Vaughn MacCaughey (Box-folder 34: 172)
    2 pages; Communities, Americanization: Education, Competition and land: Agriculture; Southern California) – Missing
  - Names gathered by George Gleason in San Diego (Box-folder 34: 173)
    1 page; Other: Illegal entry; Southern California
  - Interview with Miss Oliver, Hewitt Street School, Los Angeles (Box-folder 34: 174)
    6 pages; Americanization, Goodwill; Southern California) – Missing
  - A case of intermarriage (Box-folder 34: 175)
    1 page; Intermarriage; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - "Partial Life History of a Japanese Girl," by Gretchen Tuthill, Los Angeles, 1924 August (Box-folder 34: 176)
    5 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Family problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - Extract, Los Angeles Japanese American (Box-folder 34: 177)
    1 page; Investigations, Competition and land: Land ownership; Japanese; Southern California
  - Detailed information from Los Angeles Japanese American about Long Beach church matter relative to the case of Shimiza (Box-folder 34: 178)
    14 pages; Competition and land, Race consciousness, Communities; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - "Anti-Japanese Society Holds Meeting at Club Rooms," extract, Hollywood News, 1924 January 15 (Box-folder 34: 179)
    1 page; Race consciousness, Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Jap Invasion Is Feared in New District," extract, Hollywood News, 1924 January 17 (Box-folder 34: 180)
  - "Anti-Japanese Meeting to Be Held Tonight in Legion Club Room," extract, Hollywood News, 1923 June 18 (Box-folder 34: 181)
  - "Anti-Japanese Meeting to be Held Tonight," extract, Hollywood News, 1924 January 14 (Box-folder 34: 182)
  - Extracts from the Vancouver Daily World relating to the Asiatic problem of British Columbia, compiled by J. S. Cowper, editor (Box-folder 34: 183)
    6 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture, Race consciousness; Southern California
  - Letter to George Gleason regarding the Japanese, 1934 August 17 (Box-folder 34: 184)
    3 pages; Race consciousness, Population: Immigration; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Chapterometer, official bulletin of Southern California Chapter of Japanese Students Christian Association in North America (Box-folder 34: 185)
    9 pages; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Extract from by-laws of Constitution of the Society of American Citizens of Japanese Ancestry (Box-folder 34: 186)
    2 pages; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Japanese population in Los Angeles County, 1922 (Box-folder 34: 187)
    6 pages; Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Japanese and Mexicans in Ventura County, California," by Loretta W. Balcom, 1924 June 1 (Box-folder 34: 188)
    11 pages; Communities; Japanese and Mexican; Southern California
  - "Recreation for the Japanese in Los Angeles," by Catharine Lee Wahlstrom (Box-folder 34: 189)
    7 pages; Communities, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Japanese Young Men's Association," translation, Los Angeles Japanese American, 1924 February 6 (Box-folder 34: 190)
  - Letter from H. W. Robinson to William C. Smith regarding Long Beach Japanese Church situation (Box-folder 34: 191)
    4 pages; Race consciousness; Race; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Causes of Anti-Japanese Prejudice in California," by Lillian R. Thielen, 1923 May (Box-folder 34: 192)
    13 pages; Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Letters of Japanese to his teacher, 1921 August 26 (Box-folder 34: 193)
    7 pages; Life histories, Goodwill; Japanese and Chinese; Southern California
  - Report, two cases of controversies between the Buddhist churches and Christian churches in Pasadena and Los Angeles (Box-folder 34: 194)
    7 pages; Communities, Race; Japanese; Southern California
  - Digital copy of Box 35
  - Life history and social document of Mr. Mar, editor, Chinese Star (Box-folder 35: 195)
    2 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Chinese; Seattle) – Missing
  - Interview with Mrs. Yoshia Minami, Mrs. Tashiro, interpreter (Box-folder 35: 196)
    4 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Family problems and accommodation, Race consciousness: Political tension (Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Mrs. Yoshi Okazaki (Box-folder 35: 197)
    4 pages; Life histories, Goodwill, Americanization: Accommodation, Americanization; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Mrs. Shigosahuro Fukuhara, Mrs. Tashiro, interpreter (Box-folder 35: 198)
    4 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Accommodation, Racial traits; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Life history as social document (Box-folder 35: 199)
    6 pages; Life histories, Intermarriage, Race consciousness, Population: Immigration, Americanization; Chinese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Mrs. Tsuchiya, Miss Rumsey, interpreter (Box-folder 35: 200)
    4 pages; Life histories, Population: Immigration, Americanization: Vocational problems, Intermarriage; Japanese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview of David Yue as social document (Box-folder 35: 201)
    4 pages; Life histories, Population: Immigration, Race consciousness; Chinese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Interview with Miss Rumsey, concerning the Japanese at Eastland (Box-folder 35: 202)
  - Life history of Chin Took Hing as social document (Box-folder 35: 203)
    8 pages; Life histories,Competition and land: Business, Intermarriage, Tongs, Communities; Chinese; Seattle) - Missing
  - Life history of Ben Look (Box-folder 35: 204)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Accommodation; Chinese; Seattle) – Missing
  - Life history of John Sueng as a social document (Box-folder 35: 205)
    5 pages; Life histories, Competition and land: Labor, Contract, Americanization: Accommodation; Chinese; Seattle) - Missing